<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>enriquetaso - misc</title><link href="https://enriquetaso.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://enriquetaso.github.io/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://enriquetaso.github.io/</id><updated>2018-06-04T10:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>OPNFV Internship and Plugfest 2018</title><link href="https://enriquetaso.github.io/opnfv-internship-and-plugfest-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-04T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T10:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sofia Enriquez</name></author><id>tag:enriquetaso.github.io,2018-06-04:/opnfv-internship-and-plugfest-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OPNFV POSTER" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/plugfest-opnfv-2018-header.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Internship&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OPNFV is an open source project within The Linux Foundation that facilitates development
and evolution of Network Functions Virtualization (NFV) components across various open
source ecosystems through integration, deployment, and testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary goal while interning at &lt;a href="https://www.opnfv.org/"&gt;OPNFV&lt;/a&gt; was to containerize
VNFs running in Kubernetes and provide the applications …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OPNFV POSTER" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/plugfest-opnfv-2018-header.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Internship&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OPNFV is an open source project within The Linux Foundation that facilitates development
and evolution of Network Functions Virtualization (NFV) components across various open
source ecosystems through integration, deployment, and testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary goal while interning at &lt;a href="https://www.opnfv.org/"&gt;OPNFV&lt;/a&gt; was to containerize
VNFs running in Kubernetes and provide the applications to the community. It was a
very different experience for me interning for OPNFV because my team was based in
China. I’ve never had to work with a team in a different time zone. I learned a lot,
and it has taught me a great deal about effective communication. I can say hands down,
working as an OPNFV intern was one of the coolest things that have happened to me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite task was to containerize the &lt;a href="http://www.projectclearwater.org/"&gt;Clearwater Project&lt;/a&gt;
with the help of &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/setup/independent/create-cluster-kubeadm/"&gt;Kubeadm&lt;/a&gt;.
For those who don't want to search: Clearwater is an open source implementation of IMS
(the IP Multimedia Subsystem) designed from the ground up for massively scalable
deployment in the Cloud to provide voice, video and messaging services to millions of
users and Kubeadm for creating a single master cluster.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/opnfv/container4nfv/tree/master/src/vagrant/kubeadm_clearwater"&gt;Try it yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my internship, I have worked on a paper about the &lt;em&gt;benefits of VNFs and cloud
computing&lt;/em&gt; (in Spanish) that was selected for CoNallsi 2018 (Argentine Congress of
Engineering).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OPNFV attendees raising arms" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/plugfest-opnfv-2018-all.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Plugfest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETSI hosted OPNFV at their facilities in Sophia Antipolis for a co-located
hackfest/plugfest June 4-8, 2018. The Event focused on interoperability of the OPNFV
platform in deployment, network integration, VNF applications, etc. on the &lt;strong&gt;Fraser release&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OPNFV Plugfest the interns and Heather" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/opnfv-plugfest-heather.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over thirty people attended the event, most OPNFV members and contributors. I had a great
time hearing the sessions about OPNFV Verified Program (OVP), Barometer, installers, XCI,
and the new Lab-as-a-Service (LaaS) offering as well as hosting a hackfest where community
members collaborated on their respective projects, with sessions spanning edge computing,
MANO integration, individual project planning, and community-focused discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met incredible people there, and I'm appreciative to the Linux Foundation to help me
attend with the travel support program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OPNFV Plugfest the interns, Ray and David" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/opnfv-plugfest-ray-david.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some cool links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.opnfv.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/12/2018/09/OPNFV_ETSI_Report_FINAL.pdf"&gt;full report of the event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/blog/2018/10/cross-project-collaboration-a-focus-as-fifth-opnfv-plugfest-co-locates-with-third-etsi-plugteststm-event-to-learn-test-and-integrate-opnfv-fraser/"&gt;LF blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, my &lt;a href="https://www.opnfv.org/blog/2019/01/16/opnfv-intern-spotlight-sofia-enriquez"&gt;interview with the LF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, David, Ray, and Heather!
Thank you so much!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>OpenStack Summit Boston 2017</title><link href="https://enriquetaso.github.io/openstack-summit-boston-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-25T10:02:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-25T10:02:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sofia Enriquez</name></author><id>tag:enriquetaso.github.io,2017-05-25:/openstack-summit-boston-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Openstack&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Openstack summit boston 2017" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/boston-summit.jpg"&gt;
Before start this post, I want to thank the OpenStack Foundation to help me attend
the OpenStack Summit BOSTON! ❤&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Outreachy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, but no less important I had the opportunity to meet the great 
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marinaz"&gt;@marinaz&lt;/a&gt;: Outreachy founder 😉 She had
the great idea to meet all the interns attending to the summit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t expect that happens ever, It was an unique moment when Marina,
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vkmc"&gt;@vkmc&lt;/a&gt; (also an important Outreachy organizer)
and us had dinner, talk about the future of Outreachy and ways to
improved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the ideas I really like, is to implement a registration dashboard
to help interns know which projects are more solicited and made choose
easier. Some times you don’t know about all the companies listed and I
could be a easy way to get a look. What do you think? So, Let’s go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Outreachy dinner in Borton 2017" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/boston-outreachy-team.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;OpenStack Summit Boston&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8-11 May: This Summit a new Forum concept debuted, bringing developers
and operators to the same table for strategic planning discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Openstack summit Boston" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/boston-openstack-pic.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Edward Snowden interview 😮&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a saw on Twitter that Mark Collier was asking for suggested questions
for his interview with Edward Snowden, I shocked. This keynote interview was
amazing, an experience that I wont forget easily. From a remote location,
Snowden fielded questions that OpenStack community submitted via Twitter,
including why open source infrastructure matters in regards to data privacy
and the ethical implications of working in open source:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DIxvFuKY0KM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;WOO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the chance to be part of the Women of Openstack lunch and enjoy the
enterview to powerfull women inside the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;It’s time for Latin America&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday morning, more than 30 technical leaders from the Latin America
Movil and Claro teams met here in Boston with members of the OpenStack
Foundation to discuss plans. The result?  They now have plans to drive
community building in Latin America and bring like-minded community members
and users together through meetups and OpenStack Days events. As an Latin
member of the community I’m really waiting for this to happens!!! There’s
not OpenStack Days events near to me and I want to be part!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Projects Updates&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t attend to all of them, but here you can
&lt;a href="https://www.openstack.org/videos/summits/boston-2017/tracks/project-updates"&gt;watch all of them&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to stop here a second, and write about the OpenStack party at
Fenway Park !!! My first OpenStack city party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Openstack Party Fenway Park" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/redsocks-boston.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Openstack Party Fenway Park2" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/redboston.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>OpenStack Summit Barcelona 2016</title><link href="https://enriquetaso.github.io/openstack-summit-barcelona-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-29T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-10-29T10:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Sofia Enriquez</name></author><id>tag:enriquetaso.github.io,2016-10-29:/openstack-summit-barcelona-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Openstack Summit&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Openstack summit Barcelona 2016" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/openstack-summit-barcelona-flyer.jpg"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;OpenStack is much more than just a specific set of software with discrete features.
OpenStack is also the community that comes together to collaboratively creates
technology, innovate and puh the state of computing forward. OpenStack software
powers digital bussiness at some of the biggest companies and scientific efforts
in the world. Wal-Mart runs online retail on OpenStack. BBVA and Banco Santander
run customer-facing workloads on OpenStack . The European Organization for Nuclear
Reaseach (CERN) processes massive amounts of data from the Large Hadron Collider
to analyzer the fundamentals of physics using OpenStack. And the OpenStack community
shares lessons learned about cloud usage and the cultural shifts we face with the
changing technology landscape of today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jbryce"&gt;Jonathan Brye&lt;/a&gt;, executive director, OpenStack Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Openstack summit Barcelona 2016" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/openstack-summit-barcelona-stands.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;THE WORLD RUNS ON OPENSTACK&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;25 – 28 October 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first summit just passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four days of adventures. I have never participated in a event so massive: workshops,
talks, the Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt comfortable speaking english, as I’m Spanish-speaker, language communication
represented  one of my fears. Attending  to a international summit for first time,
with  people from all over the world… I had to be able to share an interesting
conversation. Finally, this issue was not big deal. I tried my best and I think people
understand me  😛&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love being part of this summits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Openstack summit Barcelona 2016" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/openstack-summit-barcelona-flyer2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;DESIGN SUMMIT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four-days  summit is divided between the normal summit and the Design Summit, which
is set on the last days. At Design Summits the developers community gathers to
brainstorm the requirements for the next release, discuss the implementation details
and connect with other community members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined the Cinder room to be part of the discussion, and finally met the people
behind the IRC. It was really intense and people discussed about the future of
cinder and next releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Openstack summit Barcelona 2016" src="https://enriquetaso.github.io/images/openstack-summit-barcelona-outreahy-interns.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;OUTREACHY INTERNS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met  OpenStack interns for round 12 and some of the old rounds too. It was excited
to share the activity and energy around OpenStack with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was great to see such a diverse, global group of users, developers and business
leaders at this Summits. I’m honored to be part of this community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Talks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to become a significant contributor to OpenStack if you live outside the US&lt;/em&gt;.
Since I’m from Argentina: one of my main challenge are locale requirement. I really
feel represented with this talk. 
&lt;a href="https://www.openstack.org/videos/summits/barcelona-2016"&gt;You can see all of them here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2zdLHzQLt-A" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="travel"></category></entry></feed>